

SEBASTIAN BARCKHAHN

Web Developer / Electrical Engineer

EMAIL: SDBARCKHAHN@GMAIL.COM GITHUB: GITHUB.COM/SEBASBAR PHONE: 0176 60973069

PROFILE:

Web Developer with practice in both front and back end, including practical experience gained in a two-month internship with Küchenheld, a company that makes custom made kitchens and we created a digital view room platform to allow customers and employees to follow the kitchen design process remotely. My former background is in electrical engineering with over seven years of experience in this field. I am a curious, critical and a creative person with experience in different fields and I have always worked in a teamwork environment.

With me, any company will have a committed person on its side with a fresh, creative and wide view of work and reality. I would like to eventually work with artificial intelligence, because I think it has and it will have a huge impact on our society.

EXPERIENCE

2020/12 - 2021/02

FRONTEND WEB DEVELOPER, KÜCHENHELD, GERMANY.

React project, taking a static Mock-up as reference and with a team we created an application to serve as digital room meeting the company preferences in terms of functionalities and esthetics.

2018/05 - 2019/12

PROJECT MANAGER, TPF GETINSA EUROESTUDIOS, CHILE.

Level crossing specialist (with knowledge in AREMA and CENELEC standards) Project management. Worked for the automation project of 92 level crossing of the EFE network (state rail company).

2016/02 - 2018/04

SIGNALING ENGINEER, EMPRESA DE LOS FERROCARRILES DEL ESTADO (EFE), CHILE.

Project Management, Engineer Design, Technical Specifications Design, Technical Standards Design, Development of internal regulations on signaling and rail systems for the rail network.

2013/03 - 2015/10

ELECTRICAL SYSTEM OPERATOR ENGINEER, CDEC-SING, CHILE.

Electrical faults analysis, Development of AUFLS studies, Development of Transmission Lines Restriction Studies, Protection Coordination analysis, Development of Frequency Control and Complementary Systems studies.

2011/11 - 2012/12

ELECTRICAL ENGINEER IN TRAINING, HATCH, CANADA.

Surge arresters coverage area, Ground mesh design, Luminary design, Transmission lines design, Project Hazardous Reviews, Material Take-off (MTO) for substations and substations general design.

2011/06 - 2011/11

JUNIOR ENGINEER, HATCH, CHILE.

Surge arresters coverage area, Ground mesh design, Luminary design, controlled engineering activities to maintain work, standards, adhere to timelines and meet quality assurance targets.

2010/04 - 2011/03

DEVELOPER, CENTER FOR MATHEMATICAL MODELING, CHILE/USA.

Design and development of a portable, monitoring environmental variables system, on the portable platform called BUG from Bugblab Inc. One month of internship at BugLabs Inc., New York, United States.

EDUCATION

2020/09 - 2021/02

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER, WILD CODE SCHOOL, GERMANY.

HTML5, CSS3 (Bootstrap, Material UI), Javascript ES6+, React, Redux, Node.js, Express, Databases (SQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL), REST API, JWT, Git / GitHub, Unix, Unix Terminal and Agile methodologies (Scrum, Sprint Planning, User Stories).among others working in front and back end.

2004 - 2011

ELECTRICAL ENGINEER, UNIVERSIDAD DE CHILE, CHILE.

Civil Electrical Engineer degree (6 years) specialized in electronics and power systems.

2003-2004

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE, UNIVERSIDAD DE CHILE, CHILE.

Two (2) years of a broad overview of the different university subjects.

SKILLS

- Native in Spanish, fluent in English and beginner in German.
- Cooker enthusiast.
- Music enthusiast.
- Sports.

- Science lover.
- Gamer.
- Teamwork, leadership, creative and motivated.

ACTIVITIES

- Director of the Electrical Engineering Student Center 2009.
- Member of the Swimming and Diving Branch 2007 2008.
- Member and leader of Scouts Movement of Chile 1995 2004.
- Sports are an essential part of my life.